<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on Mats Estensen 路 Personal Website 路 mxe.no</title><link>https://mxe.no/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on Mats Estensen 路 Personal Website 路 mxe.no</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 13:13:00</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mxe.no/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://mxe.no/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 13:13:00</pubDate><guid>https://mxe.no/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#e5e5e5;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-fortran" data-lang="fortran">&lt;span style="color:#fff;font-weight:bold">program &lt;/span>helloworld
&lt;span style="color:#fff;font-weight:bold">print&lt;/span> *, &lt;span style="color:#0ff;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;Hello, World!&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color:#fff;font-weight:bold">end program &lt;/span>helloworld
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The snippet above is a simple implementation of a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hello_world_program">&amp;ldquo;Hello, World!&amp;quot;&lt;/a>-program in &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran">Fortran&lt;/a>. You can try to build and execute it online &lt;a href="http://tpcg.io/1qoGse">here&lt;/a>! While Fortran may not be the most obvious language to use in 2018 it&amp;rsquo;s what I am currently working with in a project that deals with a lot of numerics (where the language still proves &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/8997039/why-is-fortran-used-for-scientific-computing/8997299#8997299">superior&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As this is the first post on this site in its current format, I&amp;rsquo;ll give a brief introduction to it. If you do not already know who I am, you can read a brief bio in my &lt;a href="about">about&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite always having some form of personal website, I&amp;rsquo;ve rarely posted much else than links to my social media profiles (see &lt;a href="https://mxe.no/">main&lt;/a> page for links) and hosted static content. And to be honest, I will most likely not regularly post to this site. For social content and short ramblings I mostly use &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/matsest">Twitter&lt;/a> (Norwegian).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This site will serve as a small digital cross road for my online persona, and contain some random posts from time to time regarding topics that interest me on both a personal and professional level. For the time being, these topics include technology, programming, information security, science and other stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As stated in the footer, this site is built with the static site generator &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> and uses a forked &lt;a href="https://github.com/matsest/hugo-coder/">Coder theme&lt;/a>. It is hosted on &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages&lt;/a>, which is configured towards my custom domain &amp;ndash; no servers to manage and open source all the way!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until next time (it &lt;em>might&lt;/em> be a while),&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; Mats&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>